<database>
  <name>massive</name>
  <description>The Massive Database contains information about all the proteomics/metabolomics datasets in massive</description>
  <release>1.0</release>
  <release_date>15-11-10</release_date>
  <entry_count>1</entry_count>
  <entries>
    <entry id="MSV000078539">
      <name>iPRG 2009: Differential proteomics in Orbitrap E. coli lysates</name>
      <description>The files in directory were generated as part of the ABRF iPRG
2009 Study.  The sample is E. coli lysate.  The five "red" RPLC
runs lack the "green" set of proteins.  The five "yellow" runs
lack the "blue" set of proteins.  Both red and yellow runs
contain a spike of BSA to enable quantitative comparison among
runs.  Proteins were reduced and alkylated by DTT and
iodoacetamide, respectively, and separated in a 1D gel.  The
proteins were trypsinized, and the peptides were added to the
in-solution digest of BSA.

In a collaboration between the Ayers Institute and Mass
Spectrometry Research Center at Vanderbilt University Medical
Center, the red and yellow samples were each separated five
times in an RPLC/MS/MS experiment lasting 184 minutes (of which
the shallow gradient lasted two hours ).  The instrument
collecting data was a Thermo LTQ-XL Orbitrap.  Eight centroided
tandem mass spectra were collected following each profile MS
scan.

Collection of these data was supported by U24 CA126479.</description>
      <cross_references>
        <ref dbkey="562" dbname="TAXONOMY"/>
      </cross_references>
      <dates>
        <date type="submission" value="14-01-28"/>
      </dates>
      <additional_fields>
        <field name="omics_type">Proteomics</field>
        <field name="full_dataset_link">http://massive.ucsd.edu/ProteoSAFe/result.jsp?task=7e3ec828c9344ccdb429140c5b646696&amp;view=advanced_view</field>
        <field name="repository">massive</field>
        <field name="instrument_platform">LTQ Orbitrap</field>
        <field name="modification">A protein modification that effectively replaces a hydrogen atom with an acetyl group.</field>
        <field name="modification">A protein modification that is produced by reaction with iodoacetamide, usually replacement of a reactive hydrogen with a methylcarboxamido group.</field>
        <field name="modification">A protein modification that effectively replaces one hydrogen atom with a hydroxyl group.</field>
        <field name="technology_type">Not available</field>
        <field name="submitter">David L. Tabb</field>
      </additional_fields>
    </entry>
  </entries>
</database>
